Christian Beam

Nokomis, FL 34275 ckbeamcoding@gmail.com (941) 416-6424

Dedicated and hardworking MERN stack specialist with over 1 year of experience in multiple front and backend technologies. I have completed a Full-Stack Certificate Bootcamp through the University of Central Florida for Web Design. My previous experience in retail has given me an unbreakable work ethic and leadership ability that will carry me into my next career in technology.

Work Experience

Inside Sales Rep

Waste Pro (Alpha Dumpsters) - Bradenton, FL March 2022 to Present

- Take customer calls and provide accurate quotes, product knowledge, and convey logistics information to Dispatch.
- De-escalate situations involving dissatisfied customers, offering understanding and support when things go wrong, and ultimately resolving the issue.
- Review customer accounts, providing updates and information about billing, sales, and logistics related issues.
- Collaborate with other sales professionals to improve customer service and sales tactics.
- Maintain contact lists and follow up with customers to continue relationships.
- Perform market analysis to establish pricing and profitability for new potential markets.

Deli Team Lead

Detwiler's Farm Market - Sarasota, FL July 2021 to February 2022

- Organized team to maintain customer service on the service counter.
- Maintained a regular cleaning schedule for equipment used on the service counter.
- Assisted with monthly inventory audits and training new hires on processes in the department.
- Provided great customer service.
- Assisted customers by providing product knowledge and resolving any questions or complaints.

Deli Manager

Detwiler's Farm Market - Sarasota, FL May 2020 to June 2021

- Trained, coached, motivated and supervised 8 employee's in products, procedures, and customer service.
- Managed product storage and rotation to avoid damages and spoilage.
- Handled all customer issues in a gracious manner in accordance with company policies.
- Ensured that displays grabbed the customers attention as well as signage.
- Understanding of products and ability to be able to step into any position and assist customers. Led by example to ensure daily objectives are being met.
- Displayed a positive attitude; promoted trust and respect among associates.

Assistant Deli Manager

Detwiler's Farm Market - Sarasota, FL

March 2016 to April 2020

- Role modeled outstanding friendly customer service and use skills and knowledge to offer solutions that meet or exceed customer expectations.
- Sliced deli meats, cheese and platters to customers request using proper deli equipment according to company guidelines.
- Submitted orders according to product on hand and inventory needs.
- Assisted in employee reviews and coaching sessions.

Education

High School Diploma

NORTH PORT HIGH SCHOOL - North Port, FL

May 2010

Skills

- Agile Methodology
- Front-End Development
- JavaScript(ES6+)
- MySQL
- Node.js
- GraphQL
- Git
- Back-end development
- Next.js
- Python (Django)
- MERN Stack

Links

https://beamchristian.github.io

https://github.com/beamchristian

https://www.linkedin.com/in/christian-beam-64b5b5a0

Certifications and Licenses

Certificate in Full Stack Coding Bootcamp Web Design

February 2022 to Present

UNIVERSITY OF CENTRAL FLORIDA - Orlando, FL